Guide to the Institute of Human Relations, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records, circa 1928-1963; Accession 19ND-A-159
  - Subject Files, 1929-1957
    - Research memoranda, 1937-1938 (Box 38, Folder 292)
    - Research memoranda: Dollard, John, 1933-1934 (Box 38, Folder 293)
    - Research memoranda:Human Factors in Social Planning, undated (Box 38, Folder 294)
    - Research plans, 1929-1947 (Box 38, Folder 295 - 300)
    - Research programs, 1929-1932 (Box 38, Folder 301 - 302)
    - Rockerfeller Foundation, Report to, 1935 (Box 39, Folder 303)
    - Reorganization memoranda, 1935 (Box 39, Folder 304)
    - Requests to publish, 1955-1958 (Box 39, Folder 305)
    - Research Committee Conference, 1930 (Box 39, Folder 306)
    - Sarason, Seymour: research activities, 1947 (Box 39, Folder 307)
    - Scandinavian project, undated (Box 39, Folder 308)
    - Science and Human Relations, 1941 (Box 39, Folder 309)
    - Science and Human Relations: child development, undated (Box 39, Folder 310)
    - Science and Human Relations: Primate Biology, undated (Box 39, Folder 311)
    - Science and Human Relations: Psychiatry (constitutional factors), undated (Box 39, Folder 312)
    - Science and Human Relations: Outlines by staff, 1946 (Box 39, Folder 313)
    - Senior research staff, 1933-1934 (Box 39, Folder 314)
    - Shuttleworth, F.K.: papers on adolescence, 1934 (Box 39, Folder 315)
    - Sigma XI: lecture, 1940 (Box 40, Folder 316)
    - Simons, L.W. Sun Chief:The Autobiography of Hopi Indian, 1942 (Box 40, Folder 317)
    - Slesinger, Donald: notes on marriage and divorce, undated (Box 40, Folder 318)
    - Smith, E.D.:Technology and Labor, 1940 (Box 40, Folder 319)
    - Social agencies: New Haven, 1931 (Box 40, Folder 320)
    - Social and Economic Aspects of Swedish Population Movements:Thomas, D., 1941 (Box 40, Folder 321)
    - Social Learning and Imitation: Miller and Dollard, 1941-1952 (Box 40, Folder 322)
    - Social Science Departments: Memoranda on the relationships of the institute, 1949 (Box 40, Folder 323)
    - Sociology: family research conferences, 1929 (Box 40, Folder 324)
    - Staff appointments, 1929-1930 (Box 40, Folder 325)
    - Statistical Bureau, 1933-1934 (Box 40, Folder 326)
    - Statistical laboratory, 1930 (Box 40, Folder 327)
    - Television project, 1948-1949 (Box 40, Folder 328)
    - Technology project: Walker, Charles R.: report on research and industrial relations, undated (Box 40, Folder 329)
    - Test catalogues, 1941-1947 (Box 40, Folder 330)
    - Theology Conferences, 1931-1937 (Box 40, Folder 331)
    - Theology Conferences, 1938-1944 (Box 41, Folder 332)
    - Toward A Science of Human Behavior: A Survey of the Work of the InstitutefMay, Mark A., 1929-1949 (Box 41, Folder 333)
    - Toward A Science of Human Behavior: bibliography materials, 1935-1945 (Box 41, Folder 334)
    - Toward A Science of Human Behavior: early outlines and suggestions from staff, 1948 (Box 41, Folder 335)
    - Toward a Science of Human Behavior: edition 3 and 4: final manuscript, 1929-1953 (Box 41, Folder 336 - 338)
    - Unemployment: Governor's Committee, undated (Box 41, Folder 339)
    - Unemployment study: Bakke-Belcher, 1933 (Box 42, Folder 340)
    - Unemployment study: Candee, L.C., 1930-1931 (Box 42, Folder 341 - 342)
    - Unemployment study: Hogg: Russell Sage Foundation, New Haven Citizens Committee and I.H.R., 1931-1932 (Box 42, Folder 343)
    - University of Hawaii, Committee on Relations with, 1934-1936 (Box 42, Folder 344)
    - Vitamin B Requirement of Man: Cowgill, G.R., 1934 (Box 42, Folder 345)
    - War activities: memoranda, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 346)
    - War effort, cooperation in: correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 42, Folder 347)
    - War panic control: memoranda, 1942 (Box 42, Folder 348)
    - Warner, Robert A.:New Haven Negroes: A Social History, 1939-1954 (Box 42, Folder 349)
    - Whiting, John W.M.Becoming a Kwoma, 1941-1951 (Box 42, Folder 350)
    - Whiting, John W.M. and Child, I.L.: paper on Hypochondriasis read to Society for Applied Anthropology, 1947 (Box 42, Folder 351)
    - Williams, P.H.:South Italian Folkways, 1938 (Box 42, Folder 352 - 353)
    - Wittenborn, J.R.: research activities, 1943-1949 (Box 43, Folder 354)
    - Work Opportunities Committee: members and minutes, 1932 (Box 43, Folder 355)
    - Work Opportunities Committee: reports, 1932-1933 (Box 43, Folder 356)
    - Winternitz, M.C.: Yale's plan for a coordinated study of man, 1929 (Box 43, Folder 357)
    - Yale University: Alumni Committee on the Institute of Human Relations, 1953-1956 (Box 43, Folder 358)
    - Yale University: Report of the Committee on Social Studies, 1953 (Box 43, Folder 359)
    - Yale University: Committee on General Studies, 1938-1958 (Box 43, Folder 360)
    - Yale University: Division of the Social Studies, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 361)
    - Yale University: Report of the President's Committee on General Education, 1953 (Box 43, Folder 362)
  - Financial Records, 1929-1963
    These records are restricted until January 1, 2039.
    - Accident reports, 1945-1951 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Account journal, 1936-1943 (Box 44, Folder 2 - 3)
    - Accounts, 1929-1938 (Box 44, Folder 4 - 10)
    - Accounts, 1951-1953 (Box 46, Folder 23 - 24)
    - Appointments and budgets, 1936-1948 (Box 46, Folder 25 - 35)
    - Appointments and budgets, 1948-1953 (Box 47, Folder 36 - 40)
    - Blue Room snack bar, 1951-1953 (Box 47, Folder 41 - 42)
    - Equipment: business and office, 1950-1956 (Box 47, Folder 43)
    - Gifts:Individual Behavior and Human Relations, 1953-1954 (Box 47, Folder 44)
    - Inventory, 1937-1950 (Box 47, Folder 45 - 48)
    - Inventory, 1952-1958 (Box 48, Folder 49 - 51)
    - Maintenance, 1936-1937 (Box 48, Folder 52)
    - Parking, 1951-1953 (Box 48, Folder 53)
    - Personnel, 1929-1938 (Box 48, Folder 54 - 61)
    - Personnel, 1938-1944 (Box 49, Folder 62 - 64)
    - Publications order register, 1937-1938 (Box 49, Folder 65)
    - Room assignments, 1948-1951 (Box 49, Folder 66 - 67)
    - Social Science Publication Fund, 1949-1953 (Box 49, Folder 68 - 69)
    - Technology project, 1949-1953 (Box 49, Folder 70 - 73)
    - Treasurer's office: correspondence, 1946-1954 (Box 49, Folder 74)
    - Work Scholarships: in-college and out-college placements, 1959-63 (Box 49, Folder 75)
  - Unrestricted Financial Records, 1938-1951
    - Accounts, 1938-1951 (Box 45, Folder 11 - 22)
  - Buildings and Specifications, 1929-1931
    - General
      - Atterbury, Grosvenor: Architectural correspondence, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Atterbury, Grosvenor: orders, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Bills: copies of, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Biochemistry laboratory, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Building reports, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - Carpentry, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Barrile, S. Manufacturing Company: orders, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Carrillo, R. and Company: orders, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Change orders, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - Child development: Gesell, Dr. Arnold, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Circle at Oak Street end of institute, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - Completion schedule, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - Conferences, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - Cubage, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 14)
      - Dark room, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 15)
      - Dictograph, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 16)
      - Dome, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 17)
      - Doors, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 18)
      - Dryer: proposed, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 19)
      - Electrical, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 20)
      - Elevators, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 21)
      - Entrance: temporary, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 22)
      - Equipment: administrative offices, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 23)
      - Equipment: Angier, Professor, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 24)
      - Equipment: estimates, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 25)
      - Equipment: furniture, 1929-1931 (Box 50, Folder 26 - 27)
      - Equipment: furniture, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 28)
      - Equipment: laboratory, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 29)
      - Equipment: orders placed, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 30)
      - Equipment: required, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 31)
      - Equipment: expert shop, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 32)
      - Fire protection, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 33)
      - Foundation, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 34)
      - Foyer, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 35)
      - Garden court, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 36)
      - Grounds, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 37)
      - Gymnasium, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 38)
      - Hardware, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 39)
      - Heating and ventilating, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 40)
      - Hospital rooms, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 41)
      - Interior finishing, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 42)
      - Kennedy; Horace W.: orders, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 43)
      - Key system, 1929-1931 (Box 51, Folder 44)
      - Kitchen, dining room and pantry, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 45)
      - Lectures, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 46)
      - Lunch room, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 47)
      - Master clock: location of, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 48)
      - Nursing staff, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 49)
      - Numbering of rooms, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 50)
      - Nurses call system, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 51)
      - Orders questioned, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 52)
      - Partitions, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 53)
      - Physical and Hydro-therapy Departments, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 54)
      - Picture moulding, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 55)
      - Plumbing, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 56)
      - Prints: correspondence, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 57)
      - Psychiatry Clinic: room and equipment, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 58)
      - Psychology Department: room and equipment, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 59)
      - Pump room and pump room equipment, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 60)
      - Purpose of vestibule, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 61)
      - Refrigeration, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 62)
      - Review of plans, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 63)
      - Rugs, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 64)
      - Sargent and Company: orders, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 65)
      - Shades, curtains and draperies, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 66)
      - Sitting rooms, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 67)
      - Sketch of building, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 68)
      - Sloan W. & J.: orders, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 69)
      - Social Science rooms, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 70)
      - Soundproff room, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 71)
      - Special patients room, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 72)
      - Stonework, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 73)
      - Telephone system, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 74)
      - Tile work, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 75)
      - Tunnel: Cedar Street from institute to Private Pavilion, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 76)
      - Tunnel: from Tower House to institute building, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 77)
      - Windows, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 78)
      - Winternitz, M.C. offices, 1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 79)
    - Buildings
      - Boardman Administration, 1929-1931 (Box 53)
        - General, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 80)
        - Allocation, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 81)
        - Alterations and Fitken future basement, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 82)
      - Clinic
        - Building reports, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 83)
        - Change orders, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 84)
        - Clocks, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 85)
        - Conferences, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 86)
        - Contracts, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 87)
        - Dental, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 88)
        - Ear, Nose and Throat, Oto-Rhino-Laryngological, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 89)
        - Electrical, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 90)
        - Elevators, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 91)
        - Equipment, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 92)
        - Eye: ophalmological, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 93)
        - Fire protection, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 94)
        - Grades and finished elevation, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 95)
        - Beating and ventilating, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 96)
        - Interior finish, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 97)
        - Key schedule, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 98)
        - Kitchen equipment: layout, serving pantry, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 99)
        - Miscellaneous, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 100)
        - Plumbing, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 101)
        - Prints: correspondence, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 102)
        - Radio, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 103)
        - Radiology, Department of, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 104)
        - Refrigeration, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 105)
        - Shades and curtains, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 106)
      - Brady Laboratory
        - General, 1929-1931 (Box 53, Folder 107 - 108)
        - Equipment, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 109)
      - Isolation
        - General, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 110)
      - Medical and Pediatrics Laboratories
        - Amphitheatre, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 111)
        - Appointments, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 112)
        - Changes in specifications, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 113)
        - Chapel, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 114)
        - Conferences, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 115)
        - Construction, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 116)
        - Corrections and criticisms, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 117)
        - Electrical, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 118)
        - Elevators, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 119)
        - Equipment, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 120 - 121)
        - Estimates, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 122)
        - Fire protection, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 123)
        - Heating and ventilating, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 124)
        - Interior finish, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 125)
        - Key system, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 126)
        - Marvin, Harold L.: rooms, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 127)
        - Milk room, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 128)
        - Miscellaneous, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 129)
        - Numbering of rooms, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 130)
        - Painting, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 131)
        - Passage to Isolation, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 132)
        - Plumbing, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 133)
        - Prints: correspondence, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 134)
        - Refrigeration, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 135)
        - Requests, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 136)
        - Schedule of completion, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 137)
        - Screens, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 138)
        - Seminar rooms, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 139)
        - Shades, curtains and draperies, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 140)
        - Shelving, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 141)
        - Telephone, 1929-1931 (Box 54, Folder 142)
      - Preventoriurn
        - General, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 143)
      - Raleigh Fitkin Memorial
        - Allocation, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 144)
        - Cornerstone, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 145)
        - Correspondence, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 146 - 148)
        - Minutes 1928, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 149)
        - Tunnel to Isolation Building, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 150)
        - Wards A, B and C, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 151)
      - Sarah Wey Thompkins Memorial
        - Architect, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 152)
        - Conferences, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 153)
        - Cornerstone, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 154)
        - Electrical, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 155)
        - Elevators, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 156)
        - Equipment, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 157)
        - Heating and ventilating, 1929-1931 (Box 55, Folder 158)
        - Miscellaneous, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 159)
        - Partitions, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 160)
        - Plumbing, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 161)
        - Prints: correspondence, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 162)
        - Refrigeration, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 163)
        - Specifications, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 164)
        - Sterilizers and stills, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 165)
      - Sterling Hall of Medicine Extension
        - Ampitheater, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 166)
        - Animal rooms, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 167)
        - Appointments, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 168)
        - Architect, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 169)
        - Artificial respiration, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 170)
        - Balance room 18, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 171)
        - Bills, copies of, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 172)
        - Change orders, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 173)
        - Checking of plans, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 174)
        - Circle, Oak Street, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 175)
        - Club room, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 176)
      - Sterling Hall of Medicine Extension
        - Completion schedule, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 177)
        - CO-2 chamber: Physiology, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 178)
        - Conferences, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 179)
        - Contractor, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 180)
        - Contracts, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 181)
        - Cubage, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 182)
        - Dark rooms, 1929-1931 (Box 56, Folder 183)
        - Doors, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 184)
        - Electrical, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 185)
        - Elevators, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 186)
        - Equipment: furniture, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 188)
        - Equipment: general, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 189)
        - Estimates, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 190)
        - Exterior, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 191)
        - Fire Protection, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 192)
        - Floors, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 193)
        - Fulton, John F., 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 194)
        - Garden Court, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 195)
        - Gas stoves, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 196)
        - Glass, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 197)
        - Grading and Fencing, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 198)
        - Hardware, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 199)
        - Heating and ventilating, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 200)
        - Interior finish, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 201)
        - Keys and locks, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 202)
        - Kitchen equipment, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 203)
        - Kjeldahl room, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 204)
        - Kymograph, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 205)
        - Laboratory equipment: general, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 206)
        - Library, 1929-1931 (Box 57, Folder 207 - 208)
        - Library specifications: memoranda, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 209)
        - Lockers, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 210)
        - Models, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 211)
        - Myograph, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 212)
        - Neuro-Anatomy, Department of, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 213)
        - Neurophysiology, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 214)
        - Numbering of rooms, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 215)
        - Observation booths: third floor, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 216)
        - Orders, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 217)
        - Passageway: from institute to extension, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 218)
        - Rharmacology, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 219)
        - Physiological Chemistry, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 220)
        - Physiology: general, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 221)
        - Physiology requests, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 222)
        - Plumbing, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 223)
        - Prints, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 224)
        - Psycho-Biology: Yerkes, Robert M., 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 225)
        - Recreational facilities, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 226)
        - Refrigeration, 1929-1931 (Box 58, Folder 227)
        - Room finishes, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 228)
        - Screens, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 229 - 230)
        - Sewers, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 231)
        - Library moving expenses, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 232)
        - Sounilproofing, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 233)
        - Stairways, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 234)
        - Steel, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 235)
        - Stonework, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 236)
        - Structural, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 237)
        - Survey of property (Block Plan), 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 238)
        - Swimming pool, animal, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 239)
        - Telephones, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 240)
        - Tunnel piping, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 241)
        - Tunnel to 350 Congress Avenue, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 242)
        - Vindow frames, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 243)
    - Sterling Pump House, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 244)
    - Winchester Laundry, 1929-1931 (Box 59, Folder 245)
    - Specifications
      - General
        - Electric wiring, elevators, heating and ventilation, 1929-1931 (Box 60, Folder 246)
        - Electric wiring, plumbing and drainage, 1929-1931 (Box 60, Folder 247)
        - Floor diagrams, 1929-1931 (Box 60, Folder 248)
        - Schedule of material and finishes, 1929-1931 (Box 60, Folder 249)
      - Clinic
        - Crane plumbing fixtures, 1929-1931 (Box 60, Folder 250)
        - Elevators, 1929-1931 (Box 60, Folder 251)
        - General contract, 1929-1931 (Box 60, Folder 252)
        - General contract, parts 2 and 3, 1929-1931 (Box 60, Folder 253)
        - Heating and ventilating, 1929-1931 (Box 60, Folder 254)
      - Farnam Memorial
        - Ward units A & B: alterations and additions parts 1, 2 and 3, 1929-1931 (Box 60, Folder 255 - 256)
      - Medical and Pediatric Laboratories
        - Old and new equipment, 1929-1931 (Box 60, Folder 257)
        - Scientific equipment, 1929-1931 (Box 60, Folder 258)
        - With Amphitheatre: labor and materials, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 259)
      - New Laboratories
        - Equipment: contracts, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 260)
        - Equipment: piping, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 261)
        - General contract, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 262)
        - General plumbing, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 263)
        - Schedule of equipment outlets, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 264)
        - Nurses Home, 1929-1931 (Box 61)
        - Electrical, plumbing and heating system, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 265)
      - Raleigh Fitkin Memorial
        - Electric wiring, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 266)
        - Elevators, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 267)
        - Labor and materials: Ward C, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 268)
        - Heating and ventilating, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 269)
        - Plumbing, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 270)
        - Refrigeration: Ward C, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 271)
        - Sterlizers, Ward C, 1929-1931 (Box 61, Folder 272)
      - Sarah Wey Tompkins Memorial Building
        - Electric wiring, 1929-1931 (Box 62, Folder 273)
        - Elevators, 1929-1931 (Box 62, Folder 274)
        - Heat and ventilating, 1929-1931 (Box 62, Folder 275)
        - Plumbing, 1929-1931 (Box 62, Folder 276)
        - Sterlizers, 1929-1931 (Box 62, Folder 277)
      - Sterling Hall of Medicine Extension
        - Labor and materials, 1929-1931 (Box 62, Folder 278)
      - Wards and Fitkin
        - Wards: south, east and west Fitkin: heating plumbing and refrigeration, 1929-1931 (Box 62, Folder 279)
  - Publications, 1928-1940
    - Bulletin of Yale University, 1931-1936 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Gesell Clinic: pediatrics, 1925-1929 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Methods and Problems of Medical Education, reprints from, 1932 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous: addresses, announcements, dedications and invitations, 1928-1933 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous: articles and reprints, 1930-1931 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous: memoranda, 1927-1934 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Papers presented before Monday Night Group, 1939-1940 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Reports of Milton C. Winternitz 1926 -1932 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Synthetic Humanism at Yale: published inThe New Republic, 1929 (Box 63, Folder 9)